[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
[Music]
with ourselves
no
knowledge is power
[Music]
well we're good to go ryan baker hello
sir welcome to the junkyard love podcast
what's up thanks for having me yeah man
i'm glad you're coming on
so i want to know one thing so i was
sitting here i was sitting here thinking
all night like
okay if you asked me this question um
what would i say to this or just try to
think of things but
honestly this is the first time that i
think that i've like
truly met and talked to you i want to
know why i keep getting other people
like hey you should jump on this guy's
podcast i mean
i've had many people could like keep
saying over and over again i'm like okay
y'all
fine i'll i'll do it like what what made
you want to start this
podcast tell me like this is the first
time i was meeting
i wanted to know a little bit about you
like what has drawn me here
wow yeah um yeah that's a good way to
start it out man
so i hope it's a good thing that people
are recommending like maybe they're
saying you know
like like-mindedness or or uh good
things like the clothing line
the persistence like i'm all about
positive
motivation manifestations and my music
and stuff and
i have a lot to say all the time and so
people are just like oh you should
really
come and talk to this guy you guys are a
lot of likes so i just want to know a
little bit about you and see
yeah so yeah i i i resonate with that i
mean because
that's kind of like my thing and um i
feel like people when they first
start listening to my podcast and they
don't really know me that's the first
thing they come back they're like oh
like you're all about positivity
and i'm like yeah i mean i guess kind of
i mean
in comparison to some other podcasts um
i'm not
my thing with the podcast is just kind
of like that everybody
has something to offer like everybody
has value and you just and if you are
able to go into a conversation with like
openness curiosity inquisitiveness
respect
joy those sort of things like you give
space to the other person to like share
something they didn't even know they had
inside of them like everybody has their
their gems just waiting to pop out of
them given the right conversation so
how i started the podcast was really a
mental health thing
like um i i've
been i see that you you do beat boxing
so i definitely want to talk about that
a little bit but um i've i've been djing
for like 10 years or so
um maybe i went to one year uh concerts
actually i was thinking about it
at the region it was like halloween
party oh nice
yeah cool yeah so that's uh yeah i mean
that that's how like
that's how you know uh how i kind of
like started my following
sort of say like i don't have a ton of
followers like i'm not i don't have like
fame or anything like that but
the uh the small amount of like people
knowing my name is is started from djing
and through djing i feel like i was able
to
build a brand where i felt confident in
saying things like on social media or
you know having an opinion and not being
like you know nervous about
sharing it or just sharing it to you
know your family members on social media
or something that's people's biggest
mistake
it's like worrying about what what other
people
think about you and also i was kind of
thinking about this too like
you know trying to like censor yourself
or
or um you know what type casting is
so basically when like an actor gets
stuck in a role
like they're the they're the fat guy you
know like
or they're the nerd or they're the
the big bad guy they they get stuck in a
role a lot of people do on tick tock on
instagram and stuff and the moment they
do something else they lose followers
they freak out they have to jump back
into the role
that's why i like fluidity like i just
want to
like let people know like this is who i
am at all times like this is me at my
lowest
and this is me at my highest i'm not
going to sugarcoat or hide anything if
you don't like it yeah
then you're probably not my friend you
know what it's like that's why why
should you hide yourself from anyone if
if
you are yourself you're more likely to
you know your vibe attracts your tribe
you know what i mean so i'm just like
unapologetically me no matter who i am
i'm not even
anyone yeah yeah yeah no that's
that's brilliant no i i like that
because we do get caught up in our
avatars we uh
the first thing that popped in my mind
when when you're like oh i'm the fat guy
or i'm the whatever
i remember uh this dude this was a
couple months ago i went to chevron
and uh this guy who was working there
like had a
had a broken leg or something like that
and i just overheard him talking
and uh someone was asking about it and
his response was like oh i should know
i'm
i'm a big guy i shouldn't be running and
like that was his reasoning for why his
leg was broken and i'm like oh man you
really like
put yourself into it into this corner
into this divot by doing that but
yeah so i i think that's why i always
have trouble
securely answering that question because
i
i i try to watch myself when i'm trying
to be like something
when i'm when i'm like oh i'm trying to
be the positive guy or i notice that i'm
that i'm maybe i'm trying to be or i'm
trying to force it that's when i'm like
oh [__] i gotta step like
am i over strangling that am i trying to
put on a performance
am i am i getting too caught up in who i
think i need to be rather than just
authentically being myself it's yeah
it's like the fun out of it too
yeah the the term act natural has always
been like mind-blowing to me i'm like
what do you how do you act
natural this doesn't make any goddamn
sense so my um
yeah i guess so so i started so you've
you've uh
heard of me through djing or heard me
djing rather that's kind of how i
started i feel like people listening to
me
um and then you know fast forward many
years
i ended up going through some mental
health stuff i had a bunch of i just
kind of had like a rough childhood that
i didn't fully
deal with and it started affecting me as
i got older and things start coming up
without
me wanting them to that sort of stuff
and so i stumbled into
podcasts um it wasn't just podcasts but
it was like
meditation you know buddhism
yoga like like you know cbd marijuana
nootropics
like just listening to all these
influential people who started changing
the way that my brain works started
changing
who i am my same my my conscious thought
i can't wait to hear about it and uh
like so i started listening to joe rogan
honestly like is probably one of my
bigger inspirations
i just started i didn't even know what
podcast really were but i stumbled onto
his clips on youtube 14 minute clips
and hearing two grown mature men
having like heartfelt honest real
conversations back and forth whether
they were kind of funny
whether they're serious whether they're
about motivation whether they're about
addiction whether they're about
depression
i was like holy [__] starts off like you
know like
the person jumping on like okay what am
i going to talk about then joe's just
there to talk and people just kind of
just like
he can just keep a conversation going
flow through it and
you create that space people just end up
being comfortable and then
word vomiting for you know for the rest
is
dude there's beauty in that word vomit
though like that's
i feel like that's really where a lot of
the gems come from you know people my
friends will come on the podcast
and they'll i don't know if i really
have much to say or they'll text me
afterwards like i don't know if i really
formed any complete sentences then
it's like i can send them a clip back
and be like dude
listen to what you just said you said
the most profound [__] for three and a
half minutes
and you think you're just coming out
here with no with no value like
everybody has value is you know yeah
absolutely
yeah so so that's a that's kind of like
how i started i just i really got into
it i'm just like really started
learning how important mental health is
and i i just really saw the value in
being able to help people by just having
conversations with a mindfulness
positive lens
i i think i see where the connection is
between you and i it's like the same
same story man
like yeah yeah so so what is your have
you lived in uh like longview kelsey
area
your whole life or i was born here i was
born here
and then i moved away
went to like 13 different schools
lived in like 70 different houses just
all over the place like no
stability and i didn't come for the best
place either
just you know dropped out once in the
military
went into this one of this wobble law
just in and out of like
homelessness and stuff like that so i i
i get it like
coming from the bottom and like i think
a big part of how i got past
all that was also you know self-help
books meditation stuff but the biggest
thing
was like learning
self-love and a lot of that and a lot of
that
you know it's like a lot of your life
can become from uh like programming
and like you know this is how you we get
addicted to struggle sometimes if you're
in it
and so it's like you kind of keep making
mistakes because
the the uncomfortableness is comforting
you know what i mean it's like a lot of
i read this book called the
10x rule by grant cardone it was when i
was in car sales
and it really kind of changed my whole
entire mindset towards everything
it's like find find
your breaking point and make that your
comfort zone and so i found like
accelerating my life to be my new uh
comfort zone if that makes sense and a
lot of and
and and to reach that level i had to let
go
i let go of like everything i actually
like
got rid of a bunch of pictures from my
past
like a bunch of notebooks and stuff got
rid of a bunch of stuff in my house
deleted my facebook
just like everything that was like my
past and like was
a ball and chain i just like one day
it's just like
it's gone and it's just like a huge
weight
huge weight lifted off me and now it's
just like
okay what's the next step what's the
next step what's the next step what's
you know my future goals uh and
and you know it's always the next step i
don't ever look back
at all because the back's not moving
forward you know what i mean so it's
like
yeah i'm i'm so focused on a vision and
i have the end goals
and i have mid-term goals but like right
now it's like
today is today and that helps me get
through you start off with
morning motivations and and
manifestations and stuff and just like
i can only be focused on growth you know
it's like the only thing in front of me
and the only thing in my life nothing
else is
even there and [__] got rid of it
dude that's
i mean that's yeah that's immense i love
that so when you talk about like
when you got rid of your old you know
facebook or you you delete your old
social media profiles
what what what about that felt like a
ball and chain because i think a lot of
people
you know i try to talk i end up talking
about social media a lot and how it like
kind of
strangles our identity and keeps us from
like you know getting in a spot where
you are
when you're really just thinking about
the future social media sometimes
gets us stuck with our past avatar of
like who the people around us
think us to be or who we thought we were
the character you've created
the character you've created exactly so
what what about getting rid of your
social media or your old accounts rather
or just kind of like moving on felt like
a ball and chain like
i think a lot of people would resonate
with with with that part
why did it feel like it was something
that was weighing you down
a lot of is being exposed
to be completely honest because when
you're younger
and you don't really have like
huge self-awareness post everything
you know like i mean i had everything on
my facebook you know it's like
back to the days when i was in partying
you know all the time not videos of me
bonging
four lokos and 40 ounces and stuff it's
just like
you know then i went through the next
stages of life you know i was in car
sales
and military was just like one thing
like then i was found out that i was
chasing like everything
every like profound thought i had i just
like
put it on there as like a a mental diary
but it was but it's and that's what a
lot of it is is just like you know
kind of like a diary but people get to
comment on your thoughts and people get
to
try and persuade your thoughts and push
their opinion
if you're if and you're an open and
outspoken person and it's just like
i'm tired of all that outside you know
uh the outside um clatter
coming in on me and and trying to uh um
oh no give give their unwanted opinion
as well so like if i had
just certain points in my life someone
can bring that back up or if you know
like someone new
like pops in and they could just pop
into a picture that's like eight years
old or something just like bring
bring it back up like in the middle like
fact checked everything that you could
possibly say it's just like
this is way too much stress and that's
like politics and all of that too is
just like
has nothing to do with my goals my
vision and just i don't know
i i didn't have a good link to my past
and i didn't have a good memory or
or a thought process
of looking back and just being able to
have
that ready um at any given moment if i
was like
upset or you know just we weak at the
time
uh you know just having having the
option to
to fuel that and just uh it was a huge
weight that was lifted off of me yeah
and just like even memories inside my
house of things you know it's just like
uh i mean i all of it yearbooks all of
it it was
it was super hard i mean because
one at one point in my life i had
everything stolen from me
like literally everyone in my house were
partying we all got roofied woke up
everything was gone everything i've ever
owned
but it was like one of the best things
that ever happened to me actually
it was a huge it was uh it was a
terrible moment in time
and i was incredibly depressed about it
but it was like a fresh start you know
what i mean
it was just like i got to start
completely back over
and and i wasn't carrying any of my
memories or anything with me anymore you
know it was just like what's the next
step what's the next day and i think
that's what gave me the mentality
was having that huge loss and being able
to start over again was like
i could literally do this at any point
moment in my life
and then still continue to push forward
and it was like
huge strength and so that's why like
getting rid of my social media and all
that was just the
same exact thing like okay this is
starting to weigh me down emotionally
and stress me out i just gone
yeah and yeah that's super dope though i
i feel like i mean of course with the
situation where you got robbed that's
not really your your first choice
because i bet you if you asked you
the day before someone was like hey if
all your stuff was gone like you'd be
all right right you'd probably be like
i'd be [__] stressed out what are you
talking about sure enough here you are
you're just fine
you know that's that's that's kind of
the beauty of i think that
i think that the truth about getting
older you know
we really begin to learn especially our
age because we have so much technology
and we're able to like
truly truly change like like really
change in just
profound ways um you know i guess kind
of like how literature literature did
for
for the society back way back when but
um
i think that when
when you know not just facebook but
social media when it first came around
it like we didn't know what it was going
to be we didn't know that it was going
to be
you know literally running a majority of
people's conscious thoughts
we didn't know that it was going to be
this like ultimate meme populator which
communicates you know like pretty pretty
intense subjects within one picture
it changes the thought the conscious
thought of all these humans that are
observing it
it becomes a job interview you have all
know a harare who is a
historian he wrote the book sapiens he
talks very elegantly about this kind of
how
we're now living in an age where
your whole life is kind of a job
interview in a sense that's a black
mirror episode
have you seen black women like was that
the one where they look into your like
they scan your eye and they can see your
memories that you like what you've done
the last one
no they're one where the chicks walking
around with their phone and they're like
oh this is a nice interaction five stars
you know what i mean and so like they
like your
your you know your overall profile like
lets you get into a better house you
know like gives you better opportunities
because people like you you have this
avatar
you're just like oh it's too much and
it's too real
it does seem like that's where we're
freaking heading man it's not yeah
that's why i don't want to remain just
like i like even i'm having my instagram
and remind people all the time like
i'm gonna post whatever the [__] on my
mind because yeah i like it if i lose 30
followers in a day
then you weren't then you shouldn't be
following me in the first place
you see i like that because i think that
instagram you know so i try to do that
too i try to not
i struggle with it because as someone
who you know
i a lot of times i identify as an artist
like it's kind of a broad
you know brush stroke but i
i do see and respect the pages that do
they do it in a certain style they post
in a certain way if you look at their
profile it's got its own
aesthetic like there is all that but um
it's not the only way to do with social
media it's not the only way to be
an authentic person it's not the only
way to be an artist it's not the only
way to be a creator whatever so
i do struggle with um yeah like like i i
want to post what's on my mind like if
i'm sitting there you know with
with my dog or something i want to be
able to post a picture of my dog and not
be like well
it would make me happy this is making me
happy i want to share my dog with my
friends who are following me
but it's not my style it's just ain't
the style that i put out there then
you're suppressing yourself in real life
things that could give you joy
it's a it's kind of a hard thing to to
wrestle with
um dude when you talked about like uh
i really thought this is sick when
you're talking about like your vision of
the future like living from a vision of
the future have you read any of joe
dispenza's work
no no he's uh he's pretty woo-woo like
it gets pretty intense he's like he runs
um uh retreats in i mean [__] i don't
know like i'm not saying i just believe
it it's pretty
intense stuff but uh there will be
people at his retreats that'll like
heal themselves like they'll be mostly
blind 70 blind or something and they'll
heal their eyesight
um they'll be like people who are
where's this guy at
joe dispenza um he he travels around i
think he's from america
but he's a doctor and he talks about
like neuroplasticity and changing your
bra i mean he's a scientist
he's intelligent um he seems like he
knows what he's talking about i don't
know enough to fact-check him completely
but
um i've done i've done a lot of like you
do some of his meditation some his
visualizations like positive
visualizations and it's [__] profound
man like it seriously feels like you're
you it's it's like a i mean it's really
kind of almost a mystical experience
sometimes if you can really lock into
some of these states but
his thing is um is
not being defined by a story of the past
but rather by a vision of the future
and i think there's some real power in
that you know and and yeah so so when
you do
like if you talk about morning
motivation or morning visualizations
do you do you find yourself doing that
like you don't really think much about
the past you kind of think about what do
i want to bring into my life
what does my future look like what do i
want to accomplish for myself what do
you there's no past man
just like what can i what can i do about
it i can't do literally anything what
can i do
the next step you know what i mean
there's only
in front of you if you if you even look
back at all
you're not moving forward you're walking
backwards the moment you turn your head
you're walking in the wrong direction i
don't even think about it at all
it's not something that even pops in my
head not even a little bit
like i wake up in the morning
look in the mirror say things you know
positive affirmation myself speak things
into existence
as if they're already there you know
like
i am a successful business owner i don't
even own a business yet you know like
i am i'm persistent i'm successful
i'm a millionaire i'm i'm not a
millionaire but i say those things you
know like
and every morning and every night and my
my next goal like i i accomplish
this today you know like i will
accomplish this
and then i i just pump myself up every
single morning
and and you know if you have things
written down
you talk about them uh you're more
likely
to to do them it's nice to have like it
tells people to have like a success
board
um you know like a vision board you have
like a picture
on the on the back if i when i went to
go like buy my house
i wasn't even deciding to buy to buy my
house like
to one day my grandpa was like you're
almost 30 you should buy a house
and i was just like i don't want to like
that's expensive and he's like
you should really do it and i'm just
like these um i was like well you know
you're
freaking 80 years old you know like try
to he's got me this far in life so
why not like i put a picture of this
house on the back of my phone and put it
on my computer
printed a picture out i had it at work i
had it everywhere like
the house that i was gonna get i
literally surrounded in every single
room and everything that i looked at
i looked at the house there's nothing i
could do to take my vision away from it
it was
literally the sole thing i was i was
focused on so when i woke up in the
morning was like
okay what can i do to make this happen
there's no
thinking about the past there's no
thinking about what happened yesterday
there's only like today and what can i
do to further myself towards my goal
you know what i mean so that's that's
kind of what i do for my my mornings
yeah man that's that's super powerful
though i mean that's
so do you have a dude are you a daily
meditator
like do you yeah what's your what got it
what got you into meditation at the
beginning you remember
um i always did you start on youtube
i've always been big into yoga
and you know
trying to calm calm my mind
you know it's like a pretty hyperactive
person and i
usually have like a lot of sporadic
thoughts and so
i try to collect myself and a lot of it
actually started when i couldn't
actually meditate it was like
when i started throat singing it's like
i don't know view it i don't know if you
know throat singing is it's like
uh mongolian or tibetan um there's like
and i and i like do that and like a
microphone
and and like i put it like on heavy uh
delay and so it's just like a constant
um
vibration of energy back and forth
between like me and a speaker and i'll
just sit there and like
do chant for a good you know 10 15
minutes and just completely zone out
there's nothing but that sound so it's
like
kind of just like letting everything go
like yeah
letting letting everything go it's like
a big thing for me
yeah yeah you kind of gotta like you do
something to distract the body mind so
you know the center of what you call
yourself of your running reality
yeah kind of kind of let's go running to
you you can get pretty hard yeah
heavy cardio um lifting going hiking
um it's like anything i can to fully
exert myself helps me just let go of
stuff too
yeah we're very similar in these ways i
i love hiking and running i'm really big
into running and it's like one of my
that's just like it's a very zen thing
for me like it's uh i'll go through
running
uh like if i'm having a super bad you
know i still suffer from days of major
depressive
disorder and uh that's just like a dumb
way to
to feel cool about the label of the name
i do depression days sometimes
um but i'll run run my face off you know
like
sometimes i'll literally be like crying
when i'm running but i'm like [__]
there's some [__] in my head that's
looping that i gotta get out of here
or i gotta go you know bring my thoughts
elsewhere i'll listen to some motivation
i'll listen some tony robbins or
something or
even just like some some good acoustic
music and kind of visualize myself
you know hanging out listening to
someone playing acoustic and that that
helps me calm so
yeah i do i i think it's pretty cool i
like that
yeah yeah yeah yeah so what do you play
any other instruments i saw you
i mean you're all up in your beatbox and
that's [__] tight i didn't want to
say one thing before i answer that
question yeah i always said that
when you after you climb a mountain all
of your other problems
are small in comparison so that's why
every time
you see every time someone sees me like
posting a picture
uh on top of a mountain or like some
huge
elevation obstacle it's usually because
i'm going through some [__] and i'm
tackling
you know i'm tackling my mind
okay so let's let's let's stick there
for a second like if there's somebody
who doesn't really if
there's a listener right now say that
they don't really they don't really [__]
with running like they don't
they they see running or cardio as like
uh
you know again with our identity like oh
cardio's not for me don't put me down
for cardio that's like another
like just catchphrase you're not down
for discipline
not down for discipline yeah i like that
well all right so so
convince these people that maybe they
need a little cardio
oh it's just i mean
the first that's why i sell i tell
anyone for for anything
you just gotta show up i mean
the moment that you take your first step
is the moment
you know like you're already there
you're already doing it
you know if you sit there and think oh
maybe i'll do this
you know later or put it up put it off
or
i can't you know just for hiking or
anything like that
or going for a walk like oh i'm too out
of shape all blots like you're never
gonna get in shape
if that's your mentality you just gotta
do it
i don't i don't know it's just like yeah
just for just for going to the gym
just like you're you're naturally gonna
get in better shape if you're just
there and just like show up
show up i mean it really is dude nike
they really have the slogan just do it
it really is
it's it's profound it's simple it makes
sense i i think that uh
mel robbins has um this 54321 i mean
it's not even
like she basically has this thing she's
a motivational
um like speaker an author and her thing
is uh
five four three two one like if it pops
into your head what you do is like oh
you're you know you're laying in bed
you're on your phone [__] around or
whatever and
uh it thought pops in your head like oh
i need to go work out
from that thought you go five four
three two and by the time you hit one
get your feet on the ground just start
that's it yeah like little things like
that are actually pretty pretty powerful
to get us through because
when you're not motivated all that stuff
seems fake at first it seems fickle it
seems like
corny almost it seems uh like
like you're i don't know you're almost
hacking yourself but you kind of have to
to get those habits built so
just kind of like remembering that that
first step
is seriously the biggest the biggest
thing like you said you know get to the
gym
all right dude you're at the gym now
you're gonna work out come on like get
get to your car
go make your breaking point your comfort
zone
yeah yeah it's like whatever is
uncomfortable
that's what you need to do and then
pretty soon it's not uncomfortable
it's how everything starts it's always
uncomfortable at first
but you just have to make that normal
mm-hmm yeah like driving like my first
time
driving difference yeah do you remember
uh do you remember the first time you
got
i mean my experience when i was like 15
or 14 or something i remember getting on
the freeway the first time i was just
white knuckled and nervous
and then now it's like i can drink four
capri suns and and snapchat
25 people at the same time while i'm
driving you know
i mean you drink four pre-suns at once
that might just i'm gonna hold four out
and just put four straws right in the
side
i don't know why you would just pour it
into a big glass i don't know
now we're thinking but i wouldn't want
it to spill because i'm driving man i'm
not gonna be reckless
yeah but but you know that that is the
thing is you gotta take that first step
you gotta trust yourself to um
to just just take that first step you
know get to the gym get your feet on the
floor like put your shoes out before bed
like i i
i always try to encourage people to to
do any sort of physical
movement every day you know because i
think we get caught up in our western
world
dude we get caught up in if it's a
workout it's so you're burning calories
or it's so you can lose
belly fat and it's like no man like you
feel so much better your mental health
is so much better just from a little bit
of movement every day and then in turn
the rest of your life gets better yeah
absolutely
yeah yeah what's your uh what's your
oh yeah i want to ask you about
beatboxing i don't want to miss out on
that so i i was glancing back through
i feel like i've seen a couple of your
beatboxing videos before maybe
just from social media but then i was
kind of like looking back through the
last couple days since we had this
podcast
um man it's sick i it's a it's a talent
that i don't have i think it's so cool
uh when did you get into beatboxing like
what's it about for you
well 16 years old we'll see i've won on
the drum set ever since i was a little
kid but
i never got one so i've always made
noises too like i have like adhd and
and i just i don't know i'm always
fidgeting or picking at something or
making random noises
and just like another thing is just help
me
zone out and let go like every time i
beatbox
it takes up all of my mental power to be
able to do that
i can't even control my eyes so that's
why sometimes i do videos like
i try to make direct contact with the
camera but if i'm going too fast it's
like
or i'm trying something way too complex
i have to wear sunglasses you know like
all over the place and just like i don't
know that
if if i'm seeing a camera and i could
see my eyes it just throws me off at
least right
too so but um i started when i was 16
and i heard the uh fat boys up broom
stick it has to hot stick it and i just
tried that and
then i saw like another video too and i
started
just started beatboxing just well you
know
dumb sounds but no one was beatboxing 16
years ago
at all so i mean just like i was doing
the most simplest stuff and i was a hit
everywhere i went so just like i just
kept doing it
pretty soon i started going to parties
and like instantly i found out that like
everyone likes beatboxing except you
know old people
or maybe your siblings you know it's
just they're just like
but like i could just walk up to any
party any situation
any building and i could just be like
hey you want me to you know like mind if
i blow your mind real quick
and i can just beatbox and i can
instantly make a friend and have
people look at me differently so i
started making it a craft
i started getting into it more and
uh when i was uh
my younger 20s i was working at a gas
station
too and never forget this guy named
steve holbert
he actually like took me to a radio
uh show and he had me uh go on the radio
and he had me like film his interviews
on youtube
somewhere still people like show me all
the time like where'd you find that
like i have uh it was years and years
ago
like almost a decade ago he did that
video and
and uh i've done like 5 000 person
stages
and for a while i was going from
place to place beatboxing wasn't i was
trying to like take it off
take off and like make it my my job
and it didn't work out so well crashed
and burned a couple of times and
actually like left me homeless
you know lost everything again it's just
like you know
you live and learn you know like you
know so i was like okay
my next plan is become financially
stable and find out a way that i can
just still
make my music and still live my life but
it's no longer i mean it's still like i
like getting my music out
but at the same time i really don't want
to become
famous at all i don't because i'm
i'm too individual i'm too opinionated
you know
yeah and i couldn't please everyone nor
do i want to i don't want to have an
avatar you know what i mean yeah
dude just like i do the music for me
yeah i like that though i mean fame is
i i think that people want to be famous
until but they they don't actually stop
and think about what being famous
is like what everyone's opinion yeah
like
like people are coming like you just
you're trying to eat and people are
coming up to you and [__]
like you're you're trying to have
conversations and people are just people
are coming up to you
as hey i want something from you like
hey can i get an autograph
hey can i can i take a picture with you
or hey just even your opinion or your
time
you know yeah exactly i'm or yeah and
people
are more willing to take you out of
context you know it's like i always
thought it was funny people will be
very very opinionated about you know
something
you know lebron or adele or ellen
degeneres says
but you know there's people around them
all the time that they don't like call
out like they don't like
try to call out or cancel you know
people around them that that make
mistakes because that's a ridiculous
thing to do and you know that these
people are human
just like you and you're like oh because
i i love these people so their mistakes
you know like i get them
and they're not just their mistakes but
when it comes to famous people
somehow it's this instant access to hey
since you're famous
you you are perfect is what you're
saying and every time you prove that
you're not i'm gonna call you out
it's just real it made you feel like a
piece of [__]
so a lot of people a lot of like famous
people turn to drugs and their lives
usually and you know end up falling
apart a lot faster than everyone else
because they have the money to
to enable that you know it's just like i
don't know
i i i enjoy my music and
i hope that like people enjoy it as well
and i inspire other people to do it but
i have no intention anymore of making
that like
my my life or touring or anything yeah
if i have a video that like goes by or
something
then so be i'm still gonna be me and
then they'll probably leave again just
like yeah
i don't care that's the good mindset to
have on it though
i mean i i think me and my friend
crystal were talking um
uh well it's been a couple days now on
the podcast but we're kind of talking
about how sometimes social media kind of
strangles the art anyway
you know like if you're if you're trying
to post something like if you're trying
to post
there's two different versions that you
could be posting like hey here's like a
cool idea
and like as a person who's perfected
this crap or as a person who is
is on the path to perfecting this craft
or enjoys doing
this thing and i want to share it with
the world and here's a cool idea
like here you go world there's that and
then there's
okay sit down pen and paper what's going
to get the most follows how do we make
sure we get the shares
like how do we make sure we get this
this if i say it like this
these people aren't going to like it so
whatever you start kind of changing the
way that you're going to do your art
so you can impress people yeah it's not
the same less
creative and that's less individual
yeah and it's not you anymore because
just like
you're not you at that point you know
you're you're trying to be what everyone
else wants
that's stressful and you lose creativity
and you lose
love for what you're doing it's like
that's the entire reason why you do it
in the first place is what you love
doing
right you know that's one thing i found
out too when i was trying to like
you know go off into performing all the
time and stuff that was just like
i'm doing this set routine over and over
again
and i was starting to like lose love for
it you know what i mean
i don't know that i totally like dropped
off for like a year or two
too just like i'm not into it anymore
then i finally like
all right i'm not performing like i can
just [__] around
you know i'm gonna get into the to the
shower and just
beatbox and let out my emotion again i
make the best
music when i'm depressed yeah right i do
i don't i do i just have like just let
it all out you know
yeah well dude it's more real it's more
like hey here's what i'm going through i
don't fully understand it but something
inside of me does so here
you know yeah like it just it falls out
of us when we was that was magnificent
yeah you like my skills
dude so so i uh um when it comes to like
performing the same routine you know
that's something that i i came across
with djing like
i would now i feel i mean it's a bit
different from covid so like i think all
my answers for djing are just kind of
like in a weird diverted direction for
right now but uh
i as much as i enjoy for the most part
just freestyling like i'll get my
playlists in order
and then i'll show up to the gig and
then i'm like i'm just gonna pull from
these playlists here
and then i'll freestyle kind of like
whatever happens but a lot of
a lot of my like good sets or like when
i'd open up for rappers or i would um
like when i was playing um like like at
a club or a bar
pretty much every single weekend i would
basically have you know
let's say like six six routines kind of
in the routines did you dj
at that the casino in town yep i did yep
club 360. i had a i had a
residency there for a while i was the
security there
now
yeah i feel like i actually remember
that now that you say that yeah
yeah no that's all coming to me now i
was like that's when i like
first first like actually met you i was
just like god i know
where do i like know you that's what i
was saying i thought that i had met you
before like
we haven't had like a full-on
conversation when we've never hung out
or anything just like yeah passing
that's completely different
yeah you probably like just held the
door open for me as i was putting all my
gear in or something you know like
i don't know um but well hey it's cool
to to re-meet you later in life isn't
that crazy how things work
but um yeah so i was playing there for a
while yeah
they they get exchanged they draw each
other to each other um
i was when it comes to routines like
you i i totally get what you were saying
about
kind of you know you almost get sick of
it or it's not not nearly as fun or it's
predictable
or for me i would hate to like as i'm
playing in the same town a lot of the
times i would hate to play the routine
and i'm like
oh like these people just heard this
exact same transition two weeks ago
maybe they don't remember they probably
don't remember
but i want to challenge myself to like
perfect my craft and then you start
realizing how much absolute time it
takes just to build
dude to build a one-hour routine and
like make it flawless and make it to
where you're comfortable playing around
within that one hour like you know
40 to 60 songs that takes weeks and
weeks of work you know yeah
it does yeah it's a job yeah
and that's that's kind of how it goes
when it's uh when it's a job i don't
i'm not djing as much right now
obviously because covet but uh
we'll see it's it's it's a it's been a
weird thing like
because a lot of my identity was tied to
it you know
a lot of a lot of my identity from
before but just when it's something that
you do
all the time you know like listening to
music constantly i'm listening and
separating into playlists and
as i'm listening to it i'm enjoying it
yeah but i'm also listening to it like
oh i have this gig coming up in two
months that's
you know i'm playing trap music so i
want to play this song for that whatever
i'm kind of always on
and now since coveted a little bit
before now i'm
i'm not listening to nearly as much
music i don't feel like i'm
working as a dj all the time
because i'm not playing on the weekends
and such so you know that could be
a positive thing time for you to reset
and get you know re-inspired with new
music because you took a break from
listening to the same [__] every day
you know now you can just go like all
right you're going to dive full back
into it and then you can be so like
oh you know i've never done this mix
before i've ever heard this song before
you know it's like
there could be a bunch of new stuff that
you haven't heard just because you
haven't been in the scene too
some new ideas i i know that i've done
that like when i'm beat boxing
and then like i'll like you know do
freestyles and stuff
and i'll just get to where i'm like i
can't think of anything new
i'm doing like no matter what i'm
resorting back to the same sound i'm
resorting back to the same loop and i
get stuck
and i'll just take i'll just take a
break you know maybe walk
come back to it you know in a week or
two sometimes
up to a month and then i'll like go go
back into it
and i have a fresh new mindset
that beats completely wiped out of my
mind anymore
you know and now i'm on to the next
sound or the next you know
and so sometimes that's dangerous
because i can forget how to do a song
but yeah
still it's refreshing to take a break so
it's probably you're probably gonna come
back
stronger yeah yeah i hope so too man i
mean
i i think that i think a lot of our the
thing about being creative the thing
about making any sort of art
is even if it's kind of created in a in
a private place
you know it's creating maybe you're
making your music in your basement
whatever like
but you need the rest of the world to
hear it like you need the opinions
maybe not the opinions of other people
but the observations of how people work
you know you take a
a break from being just inside your own
little echo chamber of nothing but music
nothing but what you're listening to
you kind of forget how like how is music
heard
how do people experience music you know
and then you go to
you know some sort of bar or some sort
of club or
you know even just a restaurant where
people are having a good time and having
a drink
you kind of are watching inadvertently
oh what are these people
how do they react to this music oh this
song comes on and it makes them that's
why i don't like
music as the job yeah
because that's all yeah it's not
you at that point you're sitting there
just like saying or like
just repeating back to me the entire
reason why i didn't like being
in that environment it's just less so
stressful man that's
when you're working it's a stressful job
yeah because you're having to be so
observant of like what's
what's reactive and what's popular i
mean and you're good at it and that's a
definitely
you definitely are i've been to uh
i now that i remember every time you
showed up there was a crowd
like literally every time like you have
a good following
and yeah and uh so i mean
listening to a crowd is definitely your
forte i don't care
i don't care that much i know i don't
care what everyone thinks or or wants
i talk truly to the core well dude it
changes
just like i said it changes what you're
doing like it's like
when i'm trying to play to the crowd
there's also a part of me that's like
i wish i could play my favorite music
you know yeah like i almost want to
almost want to create a story for them
and i did have gigs where i was able to
do that when i first started djing
that's how i was i was more like i'm the
artist i'm dj kronos
and you're going to come here what i
have to say you're going to hear what i
have to communicate through music
and then once you start getting paid for
the clubs and the bars and stuff though
you kind of have to like all right you
know like not everybody
gives a [__] about you jake like you
kind of have to just
some people just had a long week at work
and they kind of want to just listen to
their favorite song
they kind of wanted to just come to the
club and let off so there's this balance
of
let me show you cool [__] let me be an
artist up here but also
i am working for you guys it's on the
setting
yeah it is i mean if you're at like the
silver star or something i can
understand that but if you're like an
actual club
you know you don't throw on some [__]
people shake their ass too you know
[Laughter]
yeah it's a dude we'll see i mean i i
i'm curious to see what djing looks like
when it when it comes back around
um everyone's dancing six feet apart
from each other
well dude i'm afraid that they're all
gonna be like you know everybody's gonna
be like wanting me to play
the the popular tick tock song so they
can do their performed choreography yeah
tick tock like you know enthusiast
extraordinaire dude and i'm not i'm not
in my tick tock game bro i'm i'm not
i feel like an old man i i i i'm not
even like making any excuses like i feel
like someone who
someone who is trying to like be a
content creator i feel like i
i should be on tick tock but it just i
suck so much my time with
with instagram anyway you know so sam be
careful
yeah what do you think about tick tock
like does it suck you in at all or
how much time you spend on it so i it's
one thing to be very there's several
things to be careful not only is it
addictive
but the algorithms are very intense
i mean the moment that you like a video
you are entering into that algorithm
like the very moment the moment that you
spend
the moment that you watch an entire
video
you've entered into that algorithm so
it's something that you're not
interested in but you just like out
though that i like
you just create you just changed your
entire
uh experience like
from from that point on so i had a tick
tock before
and i liked some of the wrong things
and it uh
it definitely i don't know it threw off
my experience and it made it not what i
wanted it for
and it was just a bunch of stuff on my
feed that i didn't really care about
anymore and it was hard
it was really hard to be able to change
the algorithm so i just deleted it
i lost all my videos and stuff that's
fine you know i don't mind
starting over like i started over and
i've only liked um
beatboxing i've only liked music i've
only liked positive motivation
i have like three or four things that
that i
want to see even on my like 4u or
anything like that so it's like
really important that i kept it you know
specifically because the moment that you
venture out
you're screwed you've jumped into a
whole other algorithm right
everything that you see will be like
that included now yeah
so that's i i like in
tick tock i enjoy it it's fun making
little videos you
you know 15 to 40
sorry 15 second clips or something like
that just like maybe someone will do it
with it and you could have
you could put on a cool mix for your dj
and then i'll send another dj
will get into it and like chop your beat
or something like that
you have like collaborations just by
putting out
something you know it's just like it's a
cool way to meet a lot of other artists
too i think it's a great tool for a lot
of musicians
i'm seeing a lot of musicians even
famous musicians have started getting on
tick tock to
you know showcase their talents just
because they miss being in front of the
camera and people sing and
everyone's on tick tock right now so if
you like
one person you know djing or making
beats or anything like that then you're
going to see a flood of that and this
those people
are all in that same algorithm seeing
your same thing too so
it's it's definitely a good way to to
get out your name and your job and
everything
oh yeah so it's a very
it is an excellent but
also destructive tool
like i said you can go down and rob a
rabbit hole real
quick yeah absolutely i mean i
like i've done my fair shares of uh
youtube rabbit holes
and i mean even on instagram i guess too
i think that we
really have to again our age our we're
kind of the guinea pigs of
these these algorithms and like how they
work in
the way that they work 29. yeah since
we're since we're children we've been
the guinea pigs for technology as a
whole
yeah dude that's why like i honestly i i
talk about technology and social media
on my podcast actually quite a bit
because
because for me i was living many years
like
just with no awareness of it like no i
wasn't conscious of like how often it
was making me do things or how often
my opinions or choices or
you know even values are are persuaded
and
like etched over by by what i'm watching
because it's
it's going to feed you what's going to
keep you on the platform longer
and after a while they have such a good
profile of you such a good avatar like
if
you've seen the movie um the social
dilemma they kind of create
basically an avatar for a person and the
more he's clicks yes the more he clicks
like the more he interacts with this
they're like okay he likes this yep
they're good one check mark
and uh these algorithms are like
dude i don't think that even the people
at the social media companies fully
understand them we're at a point where
ai they're going into a black box
situation where
we feed the right numbers into it and it
spits out and it's like hey everything's
good cool we we met our quota we're
getting more people on the platform and
then it's like wait what did
what happened in that black box we don't
know we have no idea but everything's
good
capitalism is still going and we're like
more platform more people listening yay
and we don't understand that you know
social media and the way the algorithms
are making us act and the way
they're they're giving things they're
giving us things to think about that we
never would have thought about before as
a human species they're changing
literally who we are
at the core they're changing how we
interact with one another i mean the
whole politics
craziness is very much because of the
algorithm
and i my mentality is too combative
i hit me i mean no it's just too
combative like
i have my own i have my
own uh let's say my my mindset is too
strong
to to be persuaded and change
manipulated
oh that's just like sucked in by the
algorithms i can't i just can't even be
a part about even just like
looking at like uh all of
just like every time i see
something that is like purposely incited
to
to create stress and and and likes and
views and just like
anger and and and hate fuels
so much emotion and energy and
fear and we are
a as a society a warmongering
you know nation and have been since we
started and we
found out that you know just like what
gets what gets americans going the most
you know and the passion yo is first to
his passion to
move west and pass and to hold down the
country and passion what do we have to
be passionate about nowadays
you know just like people the entire
reason and purpose for life is
purpose itself like we have to have some
type of purpose
and we've come to come to a position
in humanity where it is easy to just
live i mean there's like we can just
be alive you know what i mean like
there's everything that we need to
sustain life there's no real challenge
anymore
what is the purpose like i've come
the through that too is just like
i've been i've been thinking about that
for a while now it's like
all right you know what is what is my
purpose you know it's just like
a lot of this has come through deleting
social media
uh it's
i always try to have some type of goal
or or envision
because like having some type of goal
gives me purpose and gives me drive and
motivation and i feel like a lot of
a lot of what you're just saying what we
feed ourselves
uh like in ingest is
as a lot of who we are so i only tried
to ingest positivity and motivation and
and this stuff and be very careful of
algorithms but
the majority of people aren't careful at
all
they just they fall right into that hate
trap those
click baits you know just like all of
those
those rabbit holes then just anything
that is designed to capture their
attention they just look at it like
sheep and i just like see the people and
just regurgitating and fighting about
stuff that doesn't even matter
yeah they don't care about it they don't
actually care about it they care about
it because everyone cares about it
and then all of a sudden tomorrow this
is not even a topic anymore but you were
so passionate about it yesterday you're
willing to fight someone now it doesn't
matter
now you're on to the next thing like
people are just like
people are going crazy and they don't
even know it their people are flat out
insane
on on facebook and they're just like so
angry at nothing it doesn't even matter
what people
are being angry about like okay politics
you're a regular average person you want
to do something about politics get into
congress otherwise you're just
bitching about it i mean yeah it does
nothing
you know it's like you're wasting your
time when you could be focusing on
betting your life or
moving forward to something or making a
a meaningful connection with someone
like i'm doing with you right now
it's like well i can be fighting with
someone on facebook that means
absolutely nothing yeah i know it's a
waste of time
dude i 100 agree i i totally agree it
really is
it's a it's a it's a it's a happy pill
almost right
it's you know it's a like hey you're
going through it you have real emotions
you have real things you got to go
through like
things are hard oh you want to make a
connection with someone but you're
nervous oh you're going to have to like
find a little courage you're going to
have to fight that fear or your social
anxiety and walk over to this person or
send a message whatever yeah just do it
exactly but we
you know we instead of doing what's hard
it's very easy to just grab our phone
man just grab
our phone like oh i'm kind of feeling a
little bit of sadness let's see what
other people are doing oh i forgot about
the sadness oh
no what did trump do cool i'm gonna
tweet at
him you know whatever like it's it's
a distraction that we don't seem to
notice is a
distraction as a culture as a society
like it's to me i feel like the more
that i kind of observe what's really
going on with all the algorithms and our
attention span
and the things that we're arguing about
like you said people are like
they're veins popping out of their neck
and their face is red and they're
screaming at people and then the next
day they're like just you know they're
just back at work
like dude like you you ain't that mad
you're
you're caught by something you're caught
in a net almost like
i almost feel uh you know
the amount of people that are caught by
our algorithms and our social media and
things they don't actually care about
is it it's way too high and i feel bad
for them i guess like
i i feel bad for them because it's not
easy it can be yeah because like
they almost don't understand that they
don't know they don't
um in this is it's simply that they
don't understand what's happening to
them
and i just i can't i cannot be a part of
it i cannot be manipulated like that
just i can't
i just it stresses me out and i like i'm
someone
you know we talked about the very
beginning of this the meditation
stuff and self-awareness and like
self-love like
i'm very aware of my body and like the
exact moment that i'm stressed out
i remove myself from the situation and i
just and i
find out exactly why there's like a a
book
uh i believe i believe is emotional
intelligence
and it's like now this
woman comes home and she goes into the
kitchen
and the husband didn't take out the
trash and she freaked out
and so she threw a dish and she went up
and into the bathroom and she was crying
and she was sitting there thinking about
it
why did she get so pissed off it's not
even that big of a deal
she was actually mad about something
several days uh
before that that she didn't deal with
and let go
and so she brought it up and she carried
it with her and stuff you know it's just
it's just i i kind of um
it's like people people get caught up
and they carry stuff with them
and and they don't let it go and if
you're
constantly absorbed by that in social
media
you know like you're constantly carrying
baggage from the next day earlier and
that you carry it throughout
your whole entire day it's going to
stress you out and i've like
pinpoint that like why am i always upset
about something like
oh every single five minutes i'm looking
at something that pisses me off
right you know it's just like dude it's
actually think about what you were
saying earlier about your house like
you wanted to manifest your house so you
put a picture of it over here you put a
picture on your phone you put a picture
here
it's in your conscious experience all
the time so it's what you're thinking
about
and the same thing can be said for
social media like if every morning you
wake up
and you wake up and the first thing that
you read is hey
your team's the good one and these guys
are the enemy here's a video of why
they're the enemy
you know like they're receiving the same
video
yeah or or they're receiving the same
with an opposite or or a different
camera lens basically painted to make
the other person look bad you know it's
all
it's it's not actually true things it's
the algorithm
not just the algorithm the algorithm is
at this point making the people who are
reporting
these things act in different ways too
but dude i i think that's i think that's
really good though um
i like how you know vigilant you seem to
be at
like not allowing you know
you know putting up good boundaries and
like knowing this is good for me so i'm
going to focus on this like i'm not i
don't have time for this [__]
it's not good for my future i know that
it's unhealthy it doesn't work for me
it's not part of who i am anymore it's
not part of what i'm going to do
um i do your vigilances seems to be um
very impressive do you when it comes to
the words
self-love what do you think about
because that is something if you asked
me
say four years ago what like jake's
self-love i would probably make like
some
corny joke and i would make fun of
people who talk about love or something
like i i
i've changed a lot in the last you know
three years or so
not that i thought love was corny or
anything before but i just i
these things i couldn't take serious so
my way of reacting there would be joking
um so teaching people about self-love
now
and how that can mean something
especially as males i think is something
that we don't
incredibly look into the word self-love
ryan like what what comes up for you
what what does it mean to you now
you can't you can't love anyone else
until you truly love yourself you just
can't you can't give that that
same energy you know it's like
carrying emotional baggage from one
relationship
to another it's like you have to take
time to learn how to love yourself
and to be okay with who you are
and to forgive yourself for what you've
done and just
you know let everything go in the moment
that you can
let everything go and just be okay with
who you are
and and love yourself the moment that
you take the first step towards real
true happiness
you know it's like if you get up and in
the morning you say
i am a good person you know i i love
myself
i'm deserving uh and you just say these
things to yourself every morning and
every night
and the thing is like kind of like what
you ingest
that's what you're telling yourself
every single day you're hearing it
you're making it a habit to be
uh loving towards yourself and
you believe it you know what i mean so
like if you say it very
you could think it all you want but if
you say it out loud be like
i am a good person people love me you
know
you say that out loud and then you
believe it
after a while and then the same thing
goes for destructive thoughts too though
you're like if you say and and it's like
a lot of things that uh
i don't know if you've ever heard a
heard of toltec wisdom
but they believe a lot of uh uh heaven
and hell is on earth
so like if someone's carrying someone
can carry hell with them by thinking
you know if someone says for instance
jacob you're stupid but and you think
about that and you hold it with yourself
and you you think you know what maybe i
am stupid they gave you hell
and you accepted hell now you're living
in hell
as you are a stupid person and
humans are the only creatures on earth
that relieve
that relive a problem or or
trauma experience or a mistake a
thousand times over we live in the hell
a lot of things with facebook that
you're reminded of that mistake over and
over again
once a year it pops up in your memories
you know just like
you're constantly in hell you know it's
it's there no one's ever just like
showing love and giving love in every
direction you're not giving your heaven
towards
everything so it's like you need to give
that to yourself and surround yourself
with that
give yourself heaven and peace you know
it's just like
just only putting in good thoughts to
yourself
and then knowing that anyone else's
opinion is literally
just an opinion it's not your own that
is a part of self-love loves anyone
calls you
you know you if someone else tells you
something
that is that is like giving you hell or
or someone who's negative towards me or
tries to bash me down or try to like use
one of my
videos against me on on social media
guess what i'm just going to block you
completely i'm not going to give you a
second chance like you want to be a part
of my
my positivity and my mission i love
myself
you can choose to be along for the ride
or you can
choose to hear about me you know what i
mean
so it's that's part of self-love and
keeping my
identity of who i am too it's like you
accept me or
or not you know be away from me i don't
even care about who
you or who you are you know it's like i
it is
it is a i feel confident in myself and i
love myself so it should be a privilege
for people to to be able to be a part of
my group and my energy you know what i
mean i don't just get i don't give out
myself to
to everyone and share my energy and my
positivity with everyone because a lot
of people can't handle it just like
you're saying if you're saying
you know what it's self-love four years
ago you would have like laugh it off and
stuff like that
okay maybe you're not ready for it and
then you're gonna give pushback and
you're gonna hate me for it because the
fact that i'm happy
you know it makes you uncomfortable
that's not my problem
you know what i mean so it's like i'm on
my mission i'm on my goal
i'm going to meet people such as you
today
when we're ready to meet maybe four
years ago neither of us were
ready to be friends or collide in the
past but that's the energy making that
full circle you know it's like
it all comes down to just you know
everything from letting go to the
facebook to all of it towards moving
forward and happiness is comes down to
self-love
yeah damn dude that was super good all
the heavens all the hells are within you
i think yeah i like what you said about
heaven and hell it reminds me of this uh
there's a story that's uh it's been
re-told i mean i've heard ram das tell
it
um i heard mike posner had a variation
of it
basically um there's
uh i'll tell the version that mike
posner told
mike poser is an artist and he does some
spoken word i'm sure you've heard of
mike poser
um but he basically really not gave
names at all
i've probably seen his face and heard
stuff but just saying a name i'm just
like i don't know
oh yeah he writes a song i took a pill
in ibiza so
but anyway so he's a good he makes
spoken word poetry
he's very good he re-told this story
though about heaven hell there was a
soldier in afghanistan
um uh he was he was stationed
and he was he was drinking a lot he's
going through it
but he kept hearing from everybody
there's everybody in the town that he
that he was stationed at they kept
saying there's there's this boy it's a
magical boy
like he's sitting under the tree and uh
he kept hearing about it and he's pissed
off he's like what are somebody talking
about this boy whatever
then finally one day he's you know he's
he's having some drinks
and he said [__] and i'm gonna go see
this boy all right and so he
he goes and he goes to the townspeople
and he finds and he finds out where the
boy is and sure enough he's walking up
he sees the tree there's there's this
young boy meditating
and uh and and he walks up to the boy
and and he
comes up and he says you're not so
special
like you you if if you're so special why
is everybody saying your magic like what
do you know about magic if you're so
magic teach me about heaven and hell
and the boy you know opens his eyes and
he looks up at the soldier and
he says teach you about heaven and hell
teach you about heaven and hell you're
drunk
you stink you're not as good you're not
a good soldier what are you doing here
and the guy and he and he he gets mad
and he's like
he freaks out he's like what do you know
what do you know and he takes his gun
and he points it at the boy
and he's mad and his veins are popping
out of his throat and he's angry
and uh the boy looks at him softly and
says that's hell
and then the man sees that the boy has
just risked his life to teach him
about hell and any the man starts
sobbing the soldier starts sobbing
and the boy says that's heaven um
and and that's the uh i don't know the
exact
the exact name of the story but it's
been retold and uh it really is
when i first heard it was really
powerful to me because
the most powerful the heaven and hells
are really within us man
you know they really are they they
really are within us and and i think
that
with things like social media um they're
they're not only within us but they can
like really be
they can be trans other people's hells
can be transferred
in the blink of an eye you know like
someone's hell can be posted online and
then suddenly
someone else is reading it and you know
they're in their hell now so
i think it's um you've got to be agile
you've got to be
like you've almost got to be swatting
away man you got to be fruit slicing
away this hell this
this negativity these curses that other
people are given and you can't just take
what's handed to you can't just take
what the algorithms are given to you
can't just take
especially if you especially if you've
been
upset and you've lived in this personal
health for a long time
you are more susceptible towards
accepting other people's
you know what i mean because you're used
to it you're conditioned to it
so it's like as a person who had a
troubled past
and and used to live my own personal
health for a long time
i'm very sensitive towards negativity
i mean i can i absorb it and it throws
me off and i personally get angry
really quick when other people are angry
around me and i know
that i know that like i know myself
i cannot be around negativity it throws
me off
big time huge energy shift i like
have to put myself in a positive
situation
or i cannot be in that situation and
it's just the part of who i
am that's why i'm so aware about it yeah
dude i i yeah i resonate with that too i
feel like now i'm a bit better at it i'm
kind of more on my chi i'm more on my
um you know i'll even occasionally do
visualizations of kind of like a
you know some sort of uh energy bubble
around me that that like
helps me stick to what i'm actually
feeling when others around me are
are getting you know angry or negative
or or violent like i
i don't get caught into it immediately
um
as much but i i think that um
some form of man it it's interesting
because we want to relate with other
people so much that sometimes we don't
see
when we're doing that we don't see when
we're like
we're chiming in just so we can like
avoid conflict
and not have to like explain who we are
and then also we just like we want to be
a part of this thing
it's like it's like you know in high
school the the the popular kids are
talking [__] about someone else and
you're just like along with them
adding in your little two cents you know
it's uh
speaking of adding in two cents i really
appreciate this conversation
you know what i mean like it's not every
day you just sit there and just
flat out have like a full-on
conversation like in depth about the
world with someone
i was like i hate small talk that's like
yeah it's really i don't talk to a lot
of people i mean
i mean i don't like to i don't like to
bash
certain people or names but i'm usually
surrounded
in especially since i lived in longview
and i'm
from a bigger city coming down to this
small little mill town
this is the entire world here and it's
just like
they have not been exposed to anything
really
and everyone's so small and
closed-minded and there's
not much to talk about not everyone has
a huge opinion about
literally anything i mean so this is
really refreshing i just wanted
to say once again that i appreciate this
and everyone was right i should have
[__]
came on to this podcast man having a
good time
that's super sweet of you ryan thank you
bro yeah i'm glad i'm having a great
time too
i'm totally uh agreeing with whoever
recommended that we
that we link up because i feel like we
have a lot of similar experiences and
you know that's for me like i said at
the beginning like the power of
the power of conversation you know
because like look i'm doing a podcast
like in and if you want to be like oh
everybody's got a podcast nowadays or
or everybody's doing whatever and it's
like i'm not trying to do that
i'm trying to it's almost like i'm not
even trying i i
this thing feels so natural to me
because it does feel so important to me
to be able to have just positively
framed conversations like
because to me i also hate small talk and
sometimes
as i'm having small talk i'm just
sitting there inside and i'm like
like why the [__] are we talking about
this i've had this conversation
three thousand times yeah or or dude
somebody will
somebody okay here's here you go some of
you somebody will meet me
oh your name's jake do you work at state
farm
i'm like i got a [__] [__]
[Music]
[Laughter]
i i just and i get it it's insane i just
feel like yes i do
yeah i do just throw them off
yeah i literally do like if you need
insurance just just let me know i mean
um but it's it's not so much about like
listen like small talk isn't something
that people should feel guilty about
they shouldn't like be down on
themselves about it
it really there is a lot of aspects like
i can't just
at all at all times i can't expect
people to be ready to talk about
the universe and like the complexities
of being a human and like so what do you
think consciousness is and they're like
dude i'm just like can i get by you to
go to the bathroom you know like i'm
just
i don't really want to talk about this
in-depth thing so i just
um yeah i i'm glad that i'm glad that
you uh
are able to like you know come to this
level of conversation and fit so
so naturally into it because it's it's
kind of just
how i try to frame a lot of
conversations you know like i'm not
always
a super energetic like like happy guy
you know i'm actually kind of an
introverted person
but in this this environment this um you
know
comfortable like vulnerable space that
can be created through a podcast
conversation
i think you get the better side of
people man like if you just give people
a chance to like
to talk and um you know like we could be
wasting our time not talking about what
we've learned in life
we could be talking about uh kim kim
kardashian and kanye west
just just split up or some or divorced
or whatever according to what i've seen
on snapchat
like you don't really get anywhere
you're just kind of repeating
other people's life drama a lot of the
times or you're just kind of saying the
same catch phrases
and this like i get value out of these
conversations like i'm going to leave
this conversation and be a changed
person
i'm going to learn something from this
interaction with you
never like spend a lot of time on
facebook
or instagram and stuff and then
someone like goes to talk about
something
and it's a video or something and you've
seen it and you could relate with them
i hate that like that is my least
favorite thing
because like i'm permanently unimpressed
you know what i mean like you're not
taught you're not telling me you sent me
a meme or something like that
i've seen it already i've seen that
video
that's just like a constant state of all
right you're not telling me anything new
we're not
talking about anything new it's like
we're talking about the same things
we've seen there's
there's no i i have this conversation
with with a lot of people like
you know like to i want to sit there and
talk about
like you know your views about the work
not like politics but like
the entire world like what are your
dreams what are your aspirations what
motivates you like that's the [__] that
i like to talk about i don't like to
like
hey do you see this on tick tock you go
along like
yes yeah yeah i'm not interested i could
just look on tick tock
and and see that i don't know someone
wants to send me i actually
i did this i have a really good friend
he likes to send me memes sometimes
but i'm following the same thing and
like he sends it because it's think hey
you know
he thinks it's funny and i'm just like
permanently like you know unimpressed on
what he's sending me because i've
already seen it so i was like you know
what you're a really good friend of me
man
i'm gonna unfollow these mean pages so
you can start impressing me and making
me laugh again
yeah i'm gonna do that for you so yeah i
actually like that
that's actually a cool idea i didn't
think that's where you're gonna go with
that i thought you were gonna say that
like you you told him to stop sending
you memes or something
but uh i like that dude that's cool you
like leave it open and so now when you
do see that stuff it is
it does catch you and it probably does
make you laugh more than it did before
yeah i'm i'm laughing at it for the
first time that's like
one thing that i do like not having
about facebook too is like
i'm not in the loop and so i can people
have something to talk about that i
don't know about you know
if i'm interested then i can choose to
listen to it otherwise i could filter
through their garbage but with everyone
that
is talking about uh i i'm impressed for
the first time so it's actually like
opening up people to be able to talk and
feel like they're teaching me something
too so there's a positive from it
yeah i like that man dude social media
is is
everyone's the same person yeah
we're all there's no individuals anymore
and that's why it's harder to have
your own opinions about everything
because it's literally everyone's
opinion
i mean how are you going to have your
own opinions when you're just cycling to
the same garbage
everyone else's and that's all you see
and hear and ingest
yeah that's why like i completely
dissociating myself from the most of
society and becoming an introvert when i
used to be a huge
outrovert you know it's just like i have
nothing in common with anyone anymore
because i just don't care about what's
going on in the world
really yeah yeah well i mean that's what
am i going to do about
you realize that people often meet you
know not as themselves not as
what they really want to communicate
because what with the realness of
themselves is so
it's so buried underneath like the
things they've been reading all day or
in all the memes that they saw and all
the whatever like i
i don't know it's it's difficult because
there is joy but like
like it if if our if our civilization
if our country is going to be like
medicated in in lethargic and like
that's just what we do is we go to our
nine to fives and then we like just on
our break we're on our phones and then
we get off and we're on our phones and
in the mornings we're on our phones
like why would you want to have a
conversation with anyone else you've
been talking to people all day
yeah it drains you man and it's like
like you're you're almost looking for
it's such a dopamine like brain hack
this thing this phone
that you're like you're reading
something funny like
you'll literally think about we
literally will put laughing my ass off
or laugh
out loud is the most normal thing ever i
mean i do it
but you're not laughing out loud you're
not laughing your ass off you're not
laughing like we've got this condensed
version of how life really is we're like
we're pretending that we're getting
genuine joy
from just kind of having a chuckle and
i i don't know i mean like there's a
balance to it i don't want to like hate
on anybody who's
who's getting some you know maybe they
they work a shitty job and they just
kind of want to like check out for a
half hour and they get off and laugh at
some funny memes like cool man i
i feel that but i i do feel
what i wish for you know people that i
love and my friends and in my listeners
is like don't [__] waste your life on
social media
don't waste your life laughing at funny
memes there's just so much more
valiantly beautiful open
experiences to life like seriously man
start start reading philosophy start
learning some cool science start
um exploring like what it means like
learn read a stoic book read a buddhist
book like read a
uh learn archery there's so many things
you could spend your time on
and dive into little interest that will
change who you are at your core
and level you up to be the person to
handle the next stage in your life
rather than just getting a little laugh
on
from a meme you know
i agree 100 yeah absolutely man
yeah i think uh i don't know it's it's
it's a hard one to navigate i i
i get worried that we're slowly falling
into being
what they depicted on the movie wally
the the disney movie the
or the pixar movie wall-e where they're
all just kind of like sitting in chairs
and they have their screens in front of
them and they
they float along and they're like this
is the most popular new color and it
changes all their jumpsuits into blue or
red or whatnot jake
you probably have a lot of people
talking about themselves on here
where do you see yourself in the future
like where is someone like you're like
what are some of your goals and
aspirations where you want to be in like
five to ten years
um that's sweet of you to ask ryan um
you know as much as i wish that i could
give you like
oh i wrote my exact goals this morning
and i know exactly what i want to do as
much as i wish that i could lay that out
for you
i don't um i imagine i just did
something for you then because now
you're gonna think about it
yeah see yeah so yeah you're starting
next time next time
next time someone asks you you should
have that like
ingrained that's true man actually yeah
you're right on that
i i'm gonna i'm gonna contemplate that
more easy
yeah well so so my thing here's my
excuse right here here's listen to me
justify it's an excuse
yeah so i it's an excuse man like
yeah envision your goals and have them
down and just like
obsess about like the next step that's
how like you create
real passion and purpose in your life
right
this is dude and it'll if you do if you
like if you can answer that question
what is my five to ten year goal right
off the top of your head
man man's like that you're just so much
more motivated because it's
already on your mind you know like
i wanna i wanna i wanna have like
another podcast with you or something
then i'll ask you that question again
i better be on top of my [__] and you'll
have it for me
yeah yeah yeah well okay look man i like
again like i said this is some sort of
justification so there is this is
there's excuses sprinkled
on this part here so i'm aware of that
but uh i just i've been through so many
profound changes covert really
again i feel like i'm blaming something
already um kova changed a lot of what
i'm doing you know i got my
audio engineering degree um i was djing
more and more i was at this point where
i'm like [__]
i can like i can enjoy my job
i can make good money like i can wake up
every day not hating my job like
i think i'm finally like kind of going
towards something that seems good for me
and so i was leaning into that and then
live events went away
so things changed and then my last
relationship like we were together for
10 years
and that's still like fairly you know a
few months back we split up and so i'm
still kind of like getting my my feet
under me
in a sense and really trying to to
project myself out like where do i like
like that's a question i guess i do ask
myself but i don't have a solid answer
for
it's like where do i see myself because
i'm just projecting towards different
areas i will say
um i'm i'm doing some some yoga teacher
training right now
yoga is pretty profound i think i could
see myself
doing doing some very i would love to
help heal people with yoga and
meditation
and all the things i learned about the
mind and psychology i would love to help
people with trauma and that sort of
thing
um and then also man this this [__]
podcast like
it it doesn't make obviously money-wise
like it doesn't make me
money right now it's like it's it's just
something that's such a passionate
project for me
this seems like something that you love
to do yeah in it
and it's it's fulfilling in this in this
weird way like i don't want to make it
seem like a bigger deal than it is i
know that a lot of people have a podcast
but to me
i really do feel i feel good about
myself after after i do these
conversations and i'll get messages from
[__] like i literally will get
messages
too just like what you said about the
yoga yeah i so
so i i wanna i wanna help people i wanna
make people feel joy but i don't want it
to be fickle like i don't want it to
like like like i don't want it to be
another thing that people get a little
giggle from the meme that i posted as
they're scrolling through and they go
like i want to make
you know profound difference in in point
people at themselves to where
they can love themselves so i don't know
exactly what that looks like
um you know i i i don't
i i'm looking forward to doing it in the
future
giving you a solid answer on this man i
i i but you're doing it you know what i
mean
just like the first step like that's
awesome uh
and and i really enjoy being on this
podcast right now man
i think it's awesome to think you're a
good person to talk to and i see
i see it going somewhere just like it's
really easy to talk to you just like
you're saying earlier
i thought i would reaffirm that to you
man yeah that's
that's very nice of you bro i i
appreciate that that's uh
that's what i want to do i want to
create a you know uh
this term is overused now like a safe
space a place where people
feel like they can take their [__]
armor off before they join the
conversation
and just like show up and like let's
just be humans in
in like like the human that's staring
across from you like i'm a flawed man
i've made many mistakes i'm very far
from perfect
still working on myself as far as even
being a podcast host like
like you mentioned adhd it's something
that i i struggle with i
you know being able to stay on the same
subject or keep the flow of a
conversation has been something i've had
to learn
something that i'm still not always
super good at some days my brain's just
[__] but
um i you're always learning you know
like this is something that
if i perfect a little bit every day
every episode that i have i get a little
bit better
if every day i feed my mind positive
content every day i feed my i read a
little bit from what i want to be
learning
um i just i imagine by the time i'm you
know
50 60 years old i'm gonna be able to
like
really know some [__] about this world
and maybe be able to give some advice to
people who really need it so
i think that's a good thing to lean into
right on man
yeah same here it's like life is
uh one big experience it's a hell of a
ride
it is and you never know what's gonna
happen day to day
you have no clue yeah you know just like
it is what it is kind of at this point
yeah dude i don't know yeah you got to
let yourself
you got to let yourself almost be humble
and and just just really admit that like
i don't know where the [__] like i don't
know where this life is going to take me
but if you can sharpen the tools to
where
whatever comes at you you're prepared
for you know like it's a it's kind of
like
anxiety depression that sort of thing i
don't think that you can always
completely get rid of it like we're
never gonna experience again like i
don't think that there's a place where
you're gonna get to and you solved all
your problems and you're like i don't
i don't ever feel sadness anymore
because i cured that side of me no man
you're a human you're going to
experience loss
you're going to experience tragedy but
if you can learn how to deal with it
learn how to deal with it yeah learn how
to just
accept it and let it go
yep yes then you can move forward
i'm all about that man yeah yeah
where do you see yourself in 10 years
well ultimately i set a goal
to be retired within 10 years i mean
it may not happen but you know
as elon musk said elon
as soon as you walk in my door i have a
portrait of him
like you know a shrine of elon musk like
when you walk in the door
like that's what you see he said
if you give yours i'm gonna take him out
of context because i don't remember the
exact quote but like if you give
yourself
uh you know a week to clean your room
it's gonna take a week you give yourself
an hour it's gonna take an hour
you know what i mean so uh
i i i have my goal to be retired
and not doing
anything but what i want to do and you
know it may be
maybe it might take longer than that but
it's going to be a hell of a lot sooner
if i have a shorter timeline you know
what i mean
so i have like i i know i want to start
a business
uh how soon i don't know it's it's a
goal of mine i'm going to try to make it
sooner than later and i want to you know
autonomize
and i want to have property and i want
to get
you know a long-term long-term
generational income through trees and
just like
i and i want to have just a spot where
i can have everything just
you know autonomized and i can just be
relaxed
and not have to worry about you know
anything but what i love
and ultimately i can
beatbox and i can you know
go hiking and i could just do anything
that my heart desires
without worrying about having to
go to work the next day that's just that
is my goal in 10 years i don't care how
it happens
what it do it all comes down to my
morning motivations
and having pictures of it on my screens
and my cell phones
and being reminded of it and just like
making my
everyday my next step what is my very
next step
towards making this happen it's just
what my day revolves around how's this
day gonna put me one quote
one day closer towards that 10-year mark
yeah
yeah that's huge man well i truly wish
that for you man that that's
i think that's perfect how it goes i
think when you when you kind of see
that that quote from elon elon is so
perfect when you kind of see the world
as a
as a almost like a game of like all
right
here's the ending like i know where i
want to be like let's just admit to
myself like
where i want to be cool done now what
what are the levels what are the stages
what are the things i need to do what
are the equations that i need to solve
to get to this you know in in
what it takes is like you got to get
your mind right so you got to wake up
every day and get your motivation
you know and and you gotta you do you do
have to put like
bumpers on your life like bowling
bumpers you know
like to where if you're floating off and
you're like oh i've been looking at
memes for a couple days or i've been
oh i made a facebook account and i've
been arguing with my aunt again oh [__]
okay i got to get my bumper back up and
get back on track you know so uh
a lot of you know video games video
games
video games are huge what do you play
games do they do that
yeah oh i'm huge in video games but
video games
are actually so incredibly healthy
towards that i mean people may think
that you know they're a waste of time
and stuff
but they're all about goals and missions
you know for the most part what's the
next you know like
what what do i have to do to progress to
the next tier how do i get this reward
you know and you go and you grind for a
long time and you finally get
like this piece of gear or this weapon
or
you know this next stage of this
research and it's just like
if you apply that to your life like
right now you're just in the grinding
stage
you know and then and then you level up
a little bit
and if you see that the problems
get more complex and harder but
everything up to that point
is way easier you've already been
through it you know what i mean it's
just like
progression of life is exactly like uh
like a strategic video game
yeah dude yeah that's that's great i
feel like you just summarized what i was
trying to say even better than i could
that was that was wonderful because
you know at the beginning of the game
when you're first trying to learn the
tutorials you can't go fight the
final boss he'll [__] you up man he'll
kill you so like exactly
you got to learn like you're only you're
only at the bottom levels right now you
gotta
quite literally level up and i i think
dude if you see life like that it's like
uh ram das uh he has he has some crazy
stories ramdas is a
spiritual teacher who used to be a
psychologist um he basically got fired
by
taking lsd with timothy larry way back
in the day
but uh he he he uh he has this thing
where uh he has a story where he he
talks to this other
entity through someone who's channeled
it it's pretty psychedelic stuff but
um the the message he brings back from
it is
um you're on earth to take the
you're you're on you you're on earth to
take the curriculum of being human
why don't you go to class and it's like
wow you know like you could let just you
could let life happen to you
or you could you can have life happening
for you like everything that happens is
okay this is this must be like the
little mini boss before i get to
to the big boss of this stage this must
be oh
i had to solve this little quest with
this person
because it gave me the the armor that i
need to get to the next level and fight
that boss or whatever it is
you know you could really start to see
life as as
dude everything that's happening to you
you just got to be like what do i learn
from this
what do i learn from this how is this
preparing me for the next stage in my
life you know
i mean there's a lot of people like
stick to the main story mode
yeah and they progress in life faster
like
you know the the the main quest
you get straight days go to college get
a good job
get your family you look good on
instagram with your family
you retire and die you're missing all of
your side quests
you're not living you're not playing the
full game you're just streamlining you
know what i mean
and that's a lot of people can get
depressed and stuff too like or they can
they get straight to the end goal they
have all the money and all this
success but they have literally no life
experience
and they're not truly cultured or are
you know experienced or
or truly like happy people you know so
i feel like a lot of the hardships in
life are
are excellent lessons and stepping
stones towards
a full circle and being cultured in your
life
you know yeah 100 man
i love that you gotta take the side
roads too you gotta take the bonus
rounds you gotta like go down there
what is it like in mario you know you
gotta go down the green pipes
occasionally you gotta just see if you
can go down that one
and then you get a couple extra coins
down there bro
don't miss out on this it's gonna take
longer to finish the game
but you know it's there's more to
experience that way
yeah well you know i mean that's the
thing you know with a video game you get
to an ending screen you get to like you
did it whatever and
you know everybody's beat a game and
you're like huh well okay
i guess i'm done with that game like
it's not like you reach enlightenment at
the end of a video game you know in in
in the end of life it's not like you get
to where you're 60 70 80 90 whatever it
is years old
and you're like huh i've learned how to
never feel sadness again i've learned
how to i've done everything i'm
completely i
arrived at a location it's like life
life is the dance you know life is the
in between it's the journey it's not the
arrival of actually getting somewhere so
as much as you got to set some goals you
got to set some like
you can't just let yourself jump all
around you got to kind of give yourself
those bumpers and sometimes like what
you're doing
you got to like really almost like
choose your goal and really start
running at it like know what stage
you're at like here's what i want to do
by the time i'm this old
so let me set the stage there but i
don't know it's
there's no arrival with like have you
seen the videos like
those like this is these 90 year old
people and they have like a sign like
tell them your experience and life and
and and how to uh you know get into old
age and they just like
hold up a sign and just says smile you
know or just like
they're just like five of them in a row
like smile be happy
you know just like that's all you have
to say in your 90 years of life i'm
almost defended
like why don't you have why don't you
have more wisdom like what did
did you not do anything like that's all
you have
just smile i mean i mean i guess that's
good advice
to be happy to get you in the good age
but i mean uh old age but i mean like
did you do you do nothing else this is
your moment to shine and you just
smile like we're asking you the most
important question
ever and your answer is smile your
entire your entire life and your entire
existence and all the side roads you've
taken to get where you're at and that's
all you have to say
you know what's going to be funny bro is
we're going to get to where seven years
old and we're gonna be like
[__] damn samara was the answer like
we're gonna understand
she just smiled more it really was that
simple i was trying to overcomplicate it
i mean i'm not i'm not dismissing it no
idea
maybe admit and i was sitting there with
my i was talking to my friend the other
day it was like
you know as much as that pisses me off
you're like what if that's just
it yeah yeah what if it's that's just
just smile you know like i'll become
nine years old one day
and you're just gonna be laughing and
smiling people are like what like what
did he figure out like he just
he he got enlightened because he just
learned to smile i don't even talk
anymore
dude you know that's i i listened to a
lot of uh
uh one of my favorite apps waking up by
sam harris and uh he has a lot of like
lectures or like uh
little you know clips about theory or
whatever and there'll be
there's literally one that i listen to
often and it's uh
it's the meaning of life it's not like
he's trying to convince you like he's
found the meaning of life
but he's basically talking about how you
know
kind of what i was just saying you know
you don't really arrive at a place where
you're never feeling
any any downfalls you don't really
arrive at a place where you're
completely happy and you'll never have a
bad experience or you're never gonna
feel sadness or you're never gonna have
loss again like
you know to love someone means that you
risk losing them in
in feeling the loss of that love so i
think
when we're when we're thinking about our
meaning of life that's something that in
our modern society we don't ever stop
the momentum of our craziness to even
slow down and be like
what am i doing like what do i want what
do
like what do i want to experience like
oh yeah i'm gonna die
like that's actually a pretty big deal
what do i want to experience because we
we almost live
as if this thing is is unlimited we we
live as if this is
like we're gonna eventually have the
chance to do whatever we want whenever
we want
um but the the fact of the matter is we
do leave this earth you know we do
there's an ending so it's like while
you're here
you know absorb it and find reasons to
make you smile i guess like
a lot of people get so caught up in the
fact that
life will end that they
don't live too you know what i mean yeah
you you think like like they it becomes
like a sticky
stuck thought like it almost debilitates
them you think thinking about death or
i mean just like it's a pretty heavy
thought you know
just like that one day your life
will end and
you know a lot of people lose hope
especially with
it goes back to what i was saying
earlier like purpose
having having a purpose a lot of people
used to flock to religion and now
religion
entirely is starting to
fade away and people are losing
faith and hope and etc and and
i'm not i'm not a religious person i
kind of gave my views on heaven and hell
earlier
um but i think a lot of people need that
as you know like you see like a lot of
uh alcoholics and and
drug addicts and stuff they turn to to
religion because it's an
excellent crutch of hope and purpose you
know like
this is what is going to you know turn
my life around i'm going to take on
this new mindset and believe in this
person because i don't believe in myself
a lot of people are are losing that
these days and they don't have that
within themselves you know so it's uh
it's it's kind of something that people
are
not really enjoying their life because
they don't you know they don't
necessarily have
you know the meaning the meaning to live
like an
actual like true purpose like what is
their purpose it's not something that
people think about anymore
you know when people go to like church
several times you know a week it's like
all right their purpose is to be a good
person
and to serve you know there's religion
and stuff
you don't have something we are
naturally as a culture since the
beginning of time and tribe mentality
and we serve a purpose towards bettering
humanity and bettering our tribe and
everything like that
back to the very beginning of our
conversation
we have reached a level on humanity
where we're self-sustaining and there's
literally nothing else for us to do
you know it's like now it's completely
out of our hands and and all
technology like the average person isn't
just going to
pick up of you know just like oh i'm
gonna
create a super computer out of
absolutely nothing today and and fly to
the moon
i don't know it's just like not
something not something that we can
really create
we could recrea we can create an app or
you know something like that but it's
like
it's almost almost all been done you
know
but like i sure would get surprised with
new things and and
new ways to reinvent things but i mean
just like
to we've we've
basically you know covered the entire
earth we're it we're the dominant
and and it's like what do we do now and
people are losing
losing a lot of people are losing sight
and becoming depressed and
feeding to facebook and and stuff like
that to blind them throughout life
you know and not really expect going out
and just be like
i'm thankful being alive you know i'm
just going to go outside and just
enjoy the weather you know go for a walk
or go for a hike and stuff
a lot of people are just you know
standing inside going to their nine to
five jobs looking at their phone playing
a game
you know they're not really living
anymore that's like especially through
kovid
people are just staying completely
indoors and not doing anything
i mean if you go to like go to like
hiking or
or you know somewhere that used to be
public or people were
living they're just dead zones now you
know
i mean sure it's it's really nice for
the avid hiker to go out and hike and
it's not completely populated
but yeah yeah
dude yeah i i agree i think that maybe
maybe like
not just social media but maybe like the
the shift in culture that social media
and i guess just the internet and our
constant connectivity brings us
is almost feeling filling a spot of
religion in in a certain way
but but i don't know i i do think that
what we do nowadays i think that
we we throw the baby out with the bath
water when it when it comes to religion
and spiritual
stuff because we
we you know you know back then the way
that a human being
learned about like their interior in
interior psychological
um like workings the workings of their
mind the human behavior
um are like getting in touch with our
intuition whatever that might mean
like learning about our emotions
learning about
um our relationships with others the way
we
learned that like that whole very
important human real stuff
has been religion like through religious
experiences not that everybody for for
all of time was always always religious
you know there's always been
you know outliers in people who didn't
didn't believe but
i think that we are at a place where you
know
nietzsche says god's dead you know in in
the last couple hundred years or
whatever
we are experiencing that and we're
trying to live with
okay we got rid of this religion stuff
because we kind of learned more about it
we kind of started asking questions we
kind of started wondering like oh maybe
that doesn't make total sense maybe this
doesn't make sense it just doesn't feel
right whatever whatever
but i think that there's powerful life
lessons about like the human psyche the
human mind
the the consciousness that we're all
experiencing
to be found in those religious texts in
those spiritual readings
in the the wisdom of of you know
like even even philosophers i guess
that's not completely religious but
um i i think that we do
need to our society needs to
somehow discover more about the true
essence
of the human psychological
bag of meat here you know i i think we
we like i said we've thrown out the baby
with the bath water
um and we don't interact with a lot of
these religious things what we should be
doing at this point is saying
all right we know so much information
we're very [__] smart we have a lot
of technology there's very smart people
that we can connect to and create new
new ideas what was good for religion
like like what were good things that we
learned cool
let's mine those let's take those out
and then let's add them what's good from
technology cool
let's mine those let's take those out
and then you start creating something
new
a new way of of living on this planet as
a as a species as
a as a human culture as a human
civilization
and um i don't know so one thing i
really like about elon musk
going back to him again yeah trying to
go he's trying to colonize mars
you know it's trying to he's giving you
know like we gave up on space
exploration
for a long time like it was decades
since the last time they shot up you
know a rocket and
space to go to a different planet and uh
you know specifically try to do anything
with mars and
he's trying to make it we're colonized
up there
you know like i don't know if he's
playing necessarily planning on
terraforming but definitely trying to
get people up there
and he's giving humanity a mission again
yes you know yeah that's something that
we can all the space race is back on
you know humanity as a whole is as
as a mission and if everyone feels like
maybe the world
is going to come to an end because of
what we've done here and it's maybe
irreversible
i feel like you know if if that was a
reality
and people are starting to try to
colonize another planet because of
i mean that's a huge amount of purpose
that he's creating for everyone
you know yeah if he can like all right
i'm dedicating my life towards the
betterment of humanity and i want you
guys to know this
i'm gonna do it without you know with or
without you and you could
choose to be a part of my mission or not
it's like there's a lot of people like
[__] it i've not nothing else you know
that i'm passionate about let's go to
mars
you know yeah let's go to mars
i mean it's pretty wild dude like i i i
think what he's
doing sometimes i have i have good
friends who don't really care for him or
that
but i'm like and it's so weird to me
because i'm like don't you
see how profound like what he's doing is
doing
the fact that he's offensive to people
who don't want to think about it
yeah man it's it's like we're
if say one of my favorite sayings uh
like for myself is easily inspired i'm
easily inspired
and he inspires me in ways that are like
unknown
i mean basically what he's doing we
think it's like oh he's trying to be the
first one in space he's trying to be
whatever kind of what he's doing is
reminding [__] that we can go
to space
like hey guys you can do like you can
build a rocket
like you just make a lot of money and
you can build a rocket and
i think now we have a lot of young
people whose heads are turning man
they're like
oh yeah i don't have to get permission
from the government and all these
i mean i'm sure you do in all the
details but
like we we've got to not they don't have
to they don't have to go through all
this school and get doctorates and
masters and stuff to become an astronaut
to
go through this whole entire program to
possibly make into it
they can just build a business and then
build their own rocket yeah
dude i mean that's an important thing
that really changes like the momentum of
where humans are going
and i think elon i mean thinking what
what the name elon musk will be
in 30 years like what he what we'll be
able to say
i'm in a textbook in a hundred years
what they're going to say about this man
that'll be wild i hope we're not using
textbooks in 100 years
oh man i don't even think about that
it's gross there
are our floating holograms in front of
us that we made
it's like oh this is elon okay
yeah you suddenly just like oh i know
everything about elon musk cool
that's that's how it's gonna work but
dude i totally agree i'm
i'm 100 team elon i think what he does
for humanity
the way that he inspired he got a nasa
shirt on and i didn't even but yeah you
got it
you're all about it i'm all about it man
i'm all about space
and aliens and space exploration and uh
you know the the betterment and the
continuation of
you're gonna be you're gonna listen to
this uh again
and go over it and so i'm gonna say it
so you can remember it
the video game dyson sphere program
it's on steam uh it's
literally everything that you're saying
right now is it oh yeah
yep you start off on a planet you mind
stuff
next thing you're building roads next
thing you're
building particle colliders for
deuteriums for
space travel and warping to go to other
planets and solar systems and then you
colonize the entire galaxy as a mining
operation to
fuel dyson spheres which are actually
real things like this game teaches you a
lot about space
and uh quantum physics and and
how to like get to those points from a
to z
and everything about it's hugely
intellectual
and uh genius and i think that you'd
really like it if you like video games
and you like space
yeah damn that sounds interesting check
that out i'm not huge on gaming but
like i love the concept of that i think
that's that's worth checking out i love
i love to think have you seen the movie
ender's game at all
i think so um it's kind of along that
concept
like they he's trained for a game and
then in the end they basically have him
um fight the actual battle but he thinks
it's a game sort of thing
but uh yeah it could be interesting to
think of the way that games and story
lines in games change
like the way that we think about what we
do as humans
very fascinating always think of a gamer
gamer yeah
that's not the same one i don't think
it's the same one i mean i could be
wrong it could be
i could be misremembering i think it was
ender's game because the guys the kid's
name was
i think ender i don't know it's
fascinating though man i
i i love what elon does um i feel like
our next episode we should just talk
about elon the whole time like
i'm like what's one thing you love about
elon it's this what's one thing that you
love about elon all day
all day i'm all on board there was
somebody on a podcast not too long ago
or maybe it was
clubhouse i was hearing something
someone who was saying his response to
becoming a billionaire was basically
like
huh back to work you know and it's so
savage like
or becoming the most rich man in the
world rather because he he technically
is like he has the title of richest man
in the world and his response to it was
basically like
cool back to work and it's like that's
have you
gone to like talk to a person and just
like
who asks someone who their role model is
or
someone they look up to or like a mentor
and they just have no answer though
like they just have no name that pops
the head
and it's just like it is so important
you have someone to mold yourself into
to look up to
have an idol you know a lot of people
like looked up
you know to religion or superman or
whatever just like literally anyone
einstein just like having mike tyson you
know just like
someone that inspires you to know that
some
stuff is possible and just in
inspiration is so heavy and huge
in your life i think it's so important
yeah
i think we should all have somebody that
we're we're kind of looking up to that's
something in the last few years i have
multiple older people that i'm like i
hope that
i can be the type of person that would
hang out with these people later in my
life because
i'm uh you know existing as the same
personality traits of this person
because they inspire me so much i want
to aspire to be them like me i'm like if
i see someone who's awesome i'm like
how could i be more like that person how
how could i shape these aspects of me
to be true to myself but also you know
tap into
to what they have and i i think that's
super important i think everybody could
use
an idol or even a few idols like
just be inspired by somebody and follow
what they do
and and trust yourself to lean into
those inspirations
i think it's humbling to you know just
like not accept like
you're the [__] you know like you could
always be better
you know it's just like even those
people but it's someone to look up to is
just healthy
yeah i totally agree ryan we're getting
up here in time i would love to ask you
one more question before we close it out
is that cool too
yeah i was starting to get tired yeah
good
cotton mouth taking a nap yeah i know
that's how it goes uh
um so my uh i've been asking a question
of this sort lately
and i feel like it really just comes up
with with great answers so i want to
stick it to you
ryan what would you say the world could
use a little more of right now
and by the world i mean discipline
discipline
yep more discipline more discipline
straight up
just no one's disciplined anymore and
it goes down to
how you wake up in the morning the stuff
that you put into
your mind when you talk to yourself in
the mirror what you say
how you eat what you how you treat your
body
what you do what you allow people to say
to you
what you read look how you spend your
time
there's complete lack of discipline and
and a lack of persistence
that's like people just need to
shut out for a little bit you know i've
worked
i mean besides right now i've got a bum
hit because i've worked so freaking hard
for so many
you know days and for so many years but
sometimes it's necessary
necessary to just put everything on hold
and grind and chase your dreams
and do what's to right to make your body
healthy and your mind healthy and put
that first
before anything and i feel like people
just don't have the discipline
to care about themselves entirely
or or have the the motivation or drive
to to even want to make a change i mean
people can
a lot of people complain just to
complain and
that's something that i just can't stand
it's like
if someone has a problem i'm going to
give them a solution i'm going to devise
it out and i'm going to tell them
exactly the steps of how to do it and a
lot of is
because i've been through the same [__]
and you know it's
people don't want to do it and stop
complaining about it
it's you know it's just people need to
have more discipline
just what you know it's
just people just need to stop
complaining and start doing
you know yeah that's uh so i can say
yeah i love that man discipline equals
freedom that's what uh jocko willing
says
and you know i think that's that's
massive i think we see discipline as
something that
like limits us but it actually opens us
up man in this
constantly distracted overly information
and i
information ties it's not a sentence but
uh like we're just getting so much
information
in thrown at us and so if we can be
disciplined and say nah [__] that i
ain't listening to that no [__] that
ain't listening to you
no [__] that like just accept
discipline man beautiful i think that's
that's a perfect answer i love it
it's great ryan thank you again man i
really appreciate this
thank you for uh acting on you know
people referencing that we should uh
link up thank you for taking that
they're right and hitting me with the
message they were right
i should have this is great vibes man
you know what i don't know if i should
have done it sooner
because everything happens when it's
supposed to happen you know
so i feel like it was great this is a
great experience i appreciate you too
yeah man yeah thanks again i'm sure the
listeners are going to get a lot out of
this so uh
we'll link up yeah we'll have to send
some text back and forth later on so
listeners take care of yourself focus on
discipline if you never really thought
about that
self love self love and discipline 100
[__] out of yourself
yeah why wouldn't you man what do you
like love yourself it's very important
uh drink drink water stretch work on
your self love
discipline this is the junkyard love
podcast it's been
me and ryan baker thanks again man we'll
talk to you later
[Music]
knowledge is power
you